# Ahmed Ghanam

Managing Editor



#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

I'm a Journalist with eight years of experience collaborating with reporters, journalists, editors, social media directors, and managing editors in all aspects of the content-creating process using project management skills with some significant independent newspapers in Egypt and Saudi Arabia.

### **EXPERTISE**

- Project Planning
- Project Management
- Stakeholder Management
- Change Management
- Risk Management

- Research
- Content development
- Business Writing
- Readability improvement
- SEO and Social Media
- Communication skills
- Strategic Thinking
- Fact-checking
- Task Estimation
- Microsoft Office

#### **EXPERIENCES**

# Managing Editor/Writer

# Al-Dustour Newspaper | 01/2020 - Present

- Researched, analyzed, and wrote a continuous improvement plan for the newspaper site using Google Analytics And Google Search Console.
- I organized, planned, and chaired the daily newsroom meetings to set the workflow. I supervised the content creation process from writing, editing, and maintaining the editorial policy until publishing, using project management skills.
- Using my research, SEO, and social media skills, I increased website visits by 30.35% from Google search after creating a search engine optimization plan and developing a social media strategy which resulted in 5.51% additional readers, compared to three months before I did the job.
- Designed, edited, proofread, and published a weekly newsletter (Al-Dustour Newsletter).

# Social Media Manager

## Al-Dustour newspaper | 04/2022 - 06/2022

- I analyzed the social media team and reassigned tasks based on its skills, which resulted in accurate task delivery.
- Removed limitations from the company's main Facebook page, which were at risk of being unpublished, and created a new verified channel on Telegram to distribute the content.
- I developed a social media strategy containing competitor research and a fresh new content strategy with ideas to develop video content, texts, audio, and live events, which resulted in a 5.51% increase in website visits and brand awareness.

## Online Editor

# Alweeam newspaper | 12/2018 - 01/2020

- I presented a full coverage of current events, including topic suggestions, editing, proofreading, and layout for the newspaper website.
- I familiarized new reporters with the newspaper stylebook and editorial policy.

### Editorial Assistant

## Al-Dustour Newspaper | 10/2017 - 01/2020

- I oversaw the content creation, editing, proofreading, and layout for publication websites.
- I set content priorities, categories, and news piece validity for publishing, coordinate with managing editors and inform editors with reasons and notes.

- I linked the managing editors, editors, copy-Editors, revisions team, photographers, and multimedia editor.
- I created a daily report on website performance during my working hours, including the quantity and quality of news.

### Journalist and Editor

# El-Tahalof Magazine | 03/2016 - 04/2017

• Using the WordPress content management system, I created news coverage, including videos and photos about selected events for the company website.

# Reporter/Copy Editor

# Al-Dustour Newspaper | 01/2014 - 10/2017

- Revised, rewrote, and edited economic articles for the newspaper site.
- I created original topics about current economic events.

### Founder

# MahallaPost.com (formerly MahallaCity.com) | 12/2014 - 01/2017

- I created the first local press site and online radio dedicated to El-Mahalla El-Kubra city news.
- I also established a business model for the project, including content, finance, and a crowdsourcing plan to manage volunteers.
- Installed, designed, and configured a website to publish the news using WordPress content management service and a Web Hosting service, and a domain name from Yahoo!

# Graphic Designer

# Sallam Group | 11/2013 - 12/2014

- I Created corporates identities for local companies including designing logos, business cards, defining colors and font, using resources from stock services.
- I designed website layouts for companies using Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Dreamweaver.

# Co-Founder & Server Administrator

# Estdafat.com | 09/2008 - 04/2010

- I established a Web hosting and Programming services company with one of my friends.
- I set up web servers, bought domain names, and created and set up website layouts using content management systems such as WordPress, Joomla, and others.
- I managed web servers with different operating systems, such as Linux, Windows, and Mac OS.
- I helped create and implement a digital marketing plan which resulted in gaining our first customers.

### **EDUCATION**

Mass Communication Diploma
Mansoura University/Dakahlia
2017

Cameras, Exposure, and Photography
Michigan State University/Online
Feb. 2017

Journalism, the future, and you!

Michigan State University/Online

Jan. 2017

Effectively delivering the news to your audience
Michigan State University/Online
Nov. 2016

What is news?
Michigan State University/Online
Oct. 2016

Gathering and Developing the News Michigan State University/Online Oct. 2016 English for Journalism
University of Pennsylvania/Online
Sept.2016

Bachelor of Classics (Greek and Latin studies)

Mansoura University/Dakahlia

2014

Graphics design and Networking Diploma
Mansoura University
2011

### **CERTIFICATES**

## **Content Writing**

Reporting on climate change
International Center for Journalists
Sept. 2022

Writing Email
Linkedin Learning
Dec. 2019

Editing and Proofreading Made Simple
Linkedin Learning
Sept. 2017

Writing Articles
Linkedin Learning
Sept. 2017

Writing Under a Deadline
Linkedin Learning
Aug. 2017

#### Video content creation

Video Editing with Final Cut Pro X
Skillshare
Mar. 2022

Storytelling for Business Video LinkedIn Feb. 2022

## Personal development

Anger Management Linkedin Learning Dec. 2022

Body Language for Leaders
Linkedin Learning
Aug. 2020

### **Project Management**

Applying Project Management in the Real
World
Google Career Certificates
Jun. 2023

Agile Project Management
Google Career Certificates
Feb. 2023

Project Execution: Running the Project
Google Career Certificates
Dec. 2022

Project Planning: Putting It All Together
Google Career Certificates
Aug. 2022

Project Initiation: Starting a Successful Project
Google Career Certificates
May. 2022

Foundations of Project Management Google Career Certificates Dec. 2021

# Entrepreneurship

Creating Your Personal Brand Linkedin Learning Jan. 2020

Introduction to Entrepreneurship Edraak إدراك Dec. 2015

### Languages

Duolingo English Test Duolingo/Online 2021

### Tools

Learning Canva Linkedin Learning Jan. 2021

Learning Slack
Linkedin Learning
Jan. 2021

Advanced Google Analytics Linkedin Learning Feb. 2020

macOS Quick Tips Linkedin Learning Jan. 2020

### Social Media Management

Creating and Managing a YouTube Channel
Linkedin Learning
Mar. 2022

How to shine on Youtube Yanfaa.com - ينفع.كوم Aug. 2021

Social Media Management 101 Yanfaa.com – ينفع.كوم July. 2021

Social Media Strategy Yanfaa.com – ينفع.كوم July. 2021

Advanced Digital Marketing nano degree
Udacity
Mar. 2021

### **VOLUNTEER ACTIVITY**

### Media Spokesman

# Socialist Popular Alliance Party | 01/2016 - 05/2017

- Created party statements and organized press conferences coordinating with party leaders.
- I implemented a new content management system to save party statements and activities in different governorates and offered an ebook library for members.
- I established new connections with media organizations and increased party publicity and awareness of party public policies.

### **ACTIVITIES/INTERESTS**

GYM, Reading, American TV Series, Walking, Egyptian Premier League, Jazz Music, and Self Development.